Jose Lopes

Google Germany GmbH Dienerstrasse 12 80331 Munich Germany

Email: jabolopes@gmail.com

Homepage: http://jabolopes.github.com

Personal

I am a Software Engineer passionate about programming language design and implementation, compilers, type systems, and functional programming. I believe in studying new and different languages in order to grow as a Software Engineer and become more fluent in programming. Languages I have learned include Haskell, F#, C++, Java, C#, among many others. At Google, I work on large scale, distributed storage systems, and I previously worked on virtualization.

Work experience

Google, Software Engineer, July 2013-present

Knowledge Discovery and Bioinformatics (KDBio), INESC-ID, Research associate, Jan 2010–Jun 2010 (with grant)

Spoken Language Systems Lab (L2F), INESC-ID, Research associate, Sep 2008–Sep 2009 (with grant)

Distributed Systems Group (GSD), INESC-ID, Research associate, Sep 2007–Sep 2008

Spoken Language Systems Lab (L2F), INESC-ID, Research associate, Sep 2007–Sep 2008

Internships

Data Analytics and Collaborative Computing Group (DACCG), Jul 2010–Sep 2010 University of Macau (UM)

Invited talks

Modern programming for Generative Design, Mar 2013 Prog λ ang, Institute for Computer Science, University of Freiburg

Modern programming for Generative Design, Jun 2012 Max Planck Institute for Software Systems (MPI-SWS)

Education

MSc in Software Engineering and Multimedia, Sep 2009–Jun 2012 Instituto Superior Técnico (IST), Technical University of Lisbon (UTL)

BSc in Information Systems and Computer Engineering, Sep 2006-Jun 2009 Instituto Superior Técnico (IST), Technical University of Lisbon (UTL)

Jose Lopes 2

Teaching

Haskell introductory course, Course facilitator, 10 weeks, 2014 Google

Compilers, Teaching assistant, Spring semester 2010 Instituto Superior Técnico (IST), Technical University of Lisbon (UTL)

Publications

Journal Articles

Programming Languages for Generative Design: A comparative study, with A. Leitão and L. Santos International Journal of Architectural Computing (IJAC) 2012

Proceedings

Illustrated Programming, with A. Leitão and L. Santos

In proceedings of the Association for Computer Aided Design in Architecture (ACADIA) 2014

Hybrid Type Systems

In Modelling and Verifying Parallel Processes (MOVEP) 2012

Collaborative Digital Design, with L. Santos and A. Leitão

In proceedings of the Education and research in Computer Aided Architectural Design in Europe (eCAADe) 2012

Portable Generative Design for CAD Applications, with A. Leitão

In proceedings of the Association for Computer Aided Design in Architecture (ACADIA) 2011

Essential language features for Generative Design, with A. Leitão

In proceedings of Compilers, Programming Languages and Related tools (CoRTA), INForum 2011

Grants

Modelling and Verifying Parallel Processes (MOVEP) 2012 student grant

Awards

Information Systems and Computer Engineering Merit Diploma 2007/2008

Information Systems and Computer Engineering Merit Diploma with scholarship 2008/2009

18th place in Portuguese National ACM Programming Contest (MIUP) 2008

53rd place in Southwestern European Regional Programming Contest (SWERC) 2007

10th place in Portuguese National ACM Programming Contest (MIUP) 2007

Last updated: March 21, 2015